how do we solve for x in this right
triangle we're going to use pythagorean
theorem pythagorean theorem says a
squared plus b squared equals c
squared a and b are the two smaller
sides and c would be the largest side
so to plug in the values we get 3
squared plus 4 squared equals c squared
3 squared is 3 times 3 which is 9
4 squared is 4 times 4 which is 16
and we'll leave c squared as c squared 9
plus 16 is 25
and that still equals c squared and then
to solve for c we will square root both
sides
square root of 25 is 5 so we get c
equals 5.
that's the answer to the question for
more math videos please check out
andymath.com
have a good one i'll talk to you soon
bye